I want to talk today about regulation, actually,
regulation and human misbehavior.
So, this is a continuation
of my previous lecture, in a
sense, which was about behavioral finance and about
human foibles.
But now I want to go on
to talk about what we do about
some of these things, and that means talk about regulation.
So, I think that a regulation of finance, financial markets
and institutions, is substantially directed at
dealing with psychological problems and the tendency for
some people to exploit human weaknesses and manipulate and
take money from other people, rather than
help them.
But I think regulation goes beyond this, because it also
has another, more technical side, and that's about making
sure that the financial system works well.
For example, regulation deals with monopolies
and externalities.
It's been talked about a
great deal that regulation has to
take account of the, why
don't I write this down, the
problem of too big to fail.
Problem that, as regulation deals with systemic problems.
Too big to fail refers
to a phenomenon that's been observed
many times in many countries,
that whenever a big firm fails,
the government bails it out.
And that's because they realize
that if this firm, especially if
it's a financial firm, collapses,
it will bring down the whole
system with it.
So that means big firms
have an implicit government guarantee.
Small firms don't.
It's not the way anyone wanted it to
be, but it happens naturally, because big firms are
the only ones that can bring the whole system down.
So this tendency then creates
an opportunity for big firms to
take more risks than small firms, because they know that
they have this free insurance policy from the taxpayers,
and so they take bigger risks, and they bring
on systemic crises.
So dealing with this is another aspect of regulation.
And it's central to regulation right
now, in the wake of the
world financial crisis.
One term, another term I
wanted to Manish entered into this,
OK?
There's two kinds of regulation.
It's called microprudential.
I think this is a relatively new word.
At least it's become popular since the financial crisis of
the 2000s, and macroprudential.
So microprudential.
Prudential sort of means regulation, dealing with
prudent standards for business.
Microprudential regulation protects the small firms, the
small people, the individuals.
Macroprudential protects the system.
So macroprudential regulation deals with the too-big-to-fail
problem, and it deals with other problems that affect the
whole system.
So macroprudential regulation.
It's a system.
In fact, it's a system.
It упомяк the whole system.
I think the history of regulation involved both of
these, but I think the mix was more microprudential than
macroprudential until recently.
So we'll talk about both of these here.
I thought I should say just something first about
regulation and regulators.
I think regulators are analogous to the referees at a
sports event.
They enforce rules.
They decide when someone has broken the rules.
And they can punish people who
fail to adhere to the rules.
But I think that's a
good analogy, because I think we
generally all appreciate the importance of referees at
sports events.
The players often argue with the referees, but the players
want them, because it wouldn't be
a very good game if we
didn't have a referee.
Because, for example, dangerous play, or play that
risks others being hurt, or deliberate hurting of other
players, would become almost necessary in order to succeed
in the game.
So this reflects a problem.
In a competitive system, there's
kind of a race to the
bottom, right?
If everyone else is doing something that you think is
shady, well, you kind of have
to do it too, or you can't
compete.
And so that means people in
the sports world or the business
world will themselves ask for regulation, or they'll try to
do it themselves as much as they can.
Just as children, when they
play on an empty field, they
play on a board.
Just as children, when they
play on an empty field, they
play on a board.
And so, there's a lot of regulation.
There's a lot.
There's no adults around who will agree on some rules.
And maybe they have a referee, I don't know.
Usually not, but they're all referees.
They're all enforcing the rules.
That's what we're talking about when we talk about
regulation.
We tend to admire the players more than the regulators.
This is true both in sports and in finance.
We should show respect for regulators and referees.
It's a profession, and they're
not losers, as some people say.
It's true, the referees in a sports league game probably
couldn't play the game very well.
They're probably too old to play it very well.
But even so, they have a different profession, right?
And some of them are
very good at what they do.
They don't attract as much attention, except when they
make mistakes.
It's the same thing with football.
It's the same thing with the regular.
The regulators that I've met
seem to me often to be
well-meaning, intelligent people.
And I think it's a career that you should consider.
So when I say I'm hoping
that this class prepares you for a
job in finance, I'm including in
that the job as a regulator.
Some people like it better, because it adheres more to
their personal sense of morality and integrity.
They would rather be in finance.
They would rather be enforcing good rules of financial
behavior than being compromised.
I think maybe it's a different personality.
When you're in the game,
I mentioned this last time, you
get compromised one way or another.
There's no avoiding that, because you've got to kind of
play to the rules, right?
And if the rules allow something that is
questionable, you may have to do that, too.
You might try.
I think you should try not to.
But reality is something that you have to do.
And it's not something that interposes.
So some people will spend years on Wall Street making
money, and they'll switch to a regulator job.
And it isn't because they failed on Wall Street.
I think it's because life offers many different kinds of
rewards.
Anyway, in this lecture, I have
five levels of regulation that I
want to talk about.
The first one is the lowest level.
It's within the firm.
And maybe people don't always talk about that as regulation,
but I'm going to count that.
Firms set up their own rules.
There's no government involved.
This is just internal.
Then there's trade groups, where a group of
firms will get together and form a trade organization.
Or a self-regulatory organization.
And they will decide on rules among them.
Then there's local government.
That would be at the
city, or province, or state level.
And then there's national.
And you can see where I'm heading.
To international.
So, those are the five kinds of regulation.
And I think that the oldest
are the ones at the top of
the group.
And as time moves on,
we're becoming more and more broad
in geographical scope.
So, I'm preserving international regulation for
the end of this lecture.
So, let me start with
number one, which is the within
firm regulation.
And I thought I would start
by just, we've talked about this
before, about the modern corporation as having a board
of directors.
And they could be called the board of regulators.
Nobody calls them that.
But I think that they
look a lot like regulators, but
they're not imposed by the government.
Remember, I said that the board of directors is the
board of directors.
I said that a team
playing a sport wants a referee.
So, companies want somebody imposing some kind of
standards on them as a group.
So, companies have boards of directors.
Now, in most companies, they have both inside directors,
who work for the firm.
And they have outside directors, who have nothing to
do with the firm, except
that they're on the board of
directors.
I think that it's really
the outside directors that make the
board of directors into a sort of regulator.
In the last lecture, I emphasized, I was talking
about how people are different.
And some people show more character than others.
That's a problem, a fundamental problem in human society.
A lot of the people who rank
very low on character end up in
jail, unfortunately.
But most of the time,
we don't want them in jail.
But we can't put them in positions of responsibility.
So, society finds some way
of kind of quarantining them, so
that they don't.
These are all uncomfortable positions.
They're not good.
These are all uncomfortable problems.
I don't know, I can't get
into all of the issues here.
But we don't want them running a company.
We want people of character running a company.
And so, in a sense,
a board of directors imposes that.
You put people on the board
who have reputations as people of
high-minded people.
That's the way it should work.
I think the way it
usually does work, people of high-minded
people.
And so, you know, you'd probably not want to propose
some shady deal to.
So, you want to have
regular meetings of these, and where
you talk about what the company is doing.
And these people impose a
kind of community standard on what
the company is doing.
And it also has an effect
on the standing of the company in
the community, because they see
the names on the board of
directors, and they think, well, this company can't be
shady, right, with these people on the board.
When you join a board of directors, you're merging your
reputation with the reputation of the company.
So, you wouldn't do it if the company looked shady.
So, I'll give you an
example of a board of directors.
I'll use our own most
familiar example, the board of directors
of Yale University.
And it's called the President and Fellows of Yale College.
And they meet regularly.
They come to campus and have their meetings.
But it's a small group of,
I don't know what the whole
number is, like 20 people.
I'll give you some examples of
the members of the Yale, they
also call it the Yale Corporation.
Richard Levin, the president of
the university, of course, is
chairman of the board.
The governor of Connecticut, Dan Malloy, has always been,
going back hundreds of years, on the board of directors.
And he's on the Yale Corporation.
So, we have the governor of the state.
I'll just give you several more examples.
Fareed Zakaria, who was born in Mumbai, India.
He's now editor of Time Magazine.
And he's the author of many intellectual books.
And he has a kind of an intellectual television show,
public TV.
And is a Yale alumnus.
So, he's on the board.
We also have Indra, maybe I should write these names.
They're hard to spell.
Fareed Zakaria.
I mentioned, and then Indra Nooyi.
That one you might have trouble spelling.
She was not, I don't think she went to Yale.
She was educated in India.
But she's president of PepsiCo.
It's a big international corporation.
She's a director at the Lincoln Center for Performing
Arts in New York.
And this is an example of interlocking directorship.
So, you judge a director partly by what other boards
they sit on.
And she's chairperson of the U.S.-India Business Council.
And she's the director of the Yale Corporation.
And I have one more
example, who's on the Yale Corporation.
Mimi Gardner Gates.
You know who she is?
She's Bill Gates' stepmother.
But maybe that's not the way to introduce her.
I just found out that
Bill Gates' mother died in 1994,
and his father remarried.
And she's the woman who ran
the, it was a Seattle art
gallery.
So, she's an art conservator.
All these people are people
who have reputations as high-minded
intellectuals and members of our community.
I don't know that Yale is
in strong need of a board of
directors.
I think we would function like an orchestra without a
conductor.
We could do all right.
But it imposes on any corporation a sort of
regulatory standard that is important.
So, a board of directors has a really important function,
because let's move away from the nonprofit.
Yale is a nonprofit organization.
Let's consider someone doing
business, a for-profit corporation.
There are way too many opportunities for sleazy behavior.
And you only are willing to invest in a
company if the sleazy behavior is somehow under control.
So, I'm going to talk about maybe the
most important kind of sleazy behavior in a company.
It's called tunneling.
Tunneling is sneaking away with value, putting it in
your own pocket if you work for a company,
rather than in the stockholders'.
The stockholders own the company.
They're supposed to get the money.
But the employees have never met the stockholders.
And they sometimes think, you know, there's
a lot of things we can do.
And let's do them.
And the money is going to come from
the stockholders and somehow end up in our pockets.
So, I'll give you just examples of tunneling.
The company has some asset and
it's going to sell it, right?
So, asset sales.
And part of the doing business.
How does the company make sure
that it gets a good price?
Well, if you work for a company and you're
in charge of the asset sale, you can tunnel.
You say, I'll sell it to
my brother-in-law at a really low price.
All right?
He'll wait a while and
then he'll pay me off later.
Okay?
That's hard to detect.
Because how do you know if you are a stockholder?
How are you going to find out?
That's stealing from the company, right?
If you sell it at a non-market price.
How does somebody know that?
I mean, the stockholders can't be looking at every deal.
So, I'll give you another example.
Contracts.
The company is signing a contract
to provide something to them regularly.
They can pay too much.
Now, it could be your brother-in-law who's running.
But, hey, let's not be so obvious about it.
It'll just be some guy that I met.
And we're both anti-social personalities.
We've just discovered each other.
And, you know, it doesn't
even have to be written down.
I'll give this contract to you over somebody else.
And I'll pay you too much.
And, you know, sometime later, you take care of me.
You know, I did it for you.
You return the favor.
This is tunneling.
Another one.
Executive compensation.
The CEO decides to pay his friends
in the company, his cronies, very high salaries.
And he would defend it if anyone
asked, but these people are worth every penny.
Who knows what somebody is worth?
Who's going to judge that?
Expropriation of corporate opportunities.
See, one of the most valuable things about
a company is that you're in the business,
and you know what's happening, right?
And your company is producing a certain kind of product.
Then someone comes along and says, you
know, I don't really want your product,
but you seem like the kind of people
who could produce something that I really need.
Something else.
And so, you as a director, as
a president of a company, you should,
you should say, okay, we can do it.
But you don't do that.
Instead you say, I'm setting up
a new company with my name.
Or my brother-in-law is setting up a new company.
And you tell him all the corporate
secrets and how he can do it.
Okay?
That's tunneling, again.
And of course, there's insider trading.
That's when people in the company,
will buy or sell their own
shares based on knowledge that they have,
that they haven't told the public yet.
So, if you know that the company is
going to collapse, you sell your shares right away.
If you know the company has some great
news, you buy them before you announce it.
That's tunneling, again, because you're
taking money out of the company
because of the opportunities you have as
part of the management of the company.
And you're not going to sell your shares.
You're going to take money out
of the management of the company.
You see how many different ways,
and I haven't listed them all.
There's many, many ways.
Companies do so many things.
So, why would you ever invest in a company?
You might think, there's a million ways
to get money out of a company.
And the people who are running it don't know me.
They don't care about me.
That's why a corporation is kind of
a delicate thing to work at all.
It has to have some
way of controlling all these things.
And there's so many of them.
And they're so complex.
I would say, that's why we have boards of directors,
and why we put people of
known reputations on boards of directors.
So, this is maybe the most essential kind of regulation.
And it's within firm.
So, if you ever, and you
may someday be serving on a board,
the thing you have to remember
is that a board member has,
if you ever agree to serve on a board,
I think you should interpret it as
a moral obligation that you have taken on
to prevent all of these things.
Okay?
And to make sure that the
business is run in a high-minded way.
And remember that your reputation is at stake,
because you're part of the company.
But it's more than that.
It's a moral duty.
So, you have what's called the
duty of care as a board member.
Duty of care is a duty of care.
Duty of care is a duty to
act as a reasonable, prudent, rational person would.
That means you have to make
sure that you're getting the information,
you're watching, you're being careful about
your obligation as a board member.
You are not managing the company.
You are watching the management of the company.
And you don't follow every detail,
but you have to follow enough that
you act as a sort of regulator.
And you have to know what you're doing.
You also have a duty of loyalty.
And that's usually interpreted
as loyalty to the shareholders.
I would say it's expanding.
Now, there's more and more
talk of corporate social responsibility
and the loyalties that you have to other people,
members of the community at large.
But I'd say that, let's just start from the beginning.
Because there's so much temptation to steal money,
to tunnel money out of corporations,
it probably remains true that your main duty of loyalty
is to the actual shareholders.
Because they're the ones who put up the money
and they're expecting to get a profit back.
So, if you ever serve on the board of directors,
I think you may become, it may seem,
many board members don't view
it as a very significant thing.
They think, well, it's just an
honor to be on a board
and I just show up at four meetings a year.
And we listen to a presentation
from the CEO and we say, fine.
That's not what you should be doing.
I think one has to kind of notice the ambiance.
You have to use your
intuitive judgment as a board member.
About, is this an up and up firm?
Is there a good atmosphere here?
Anyway, I wanted to move up.
So, that was my first thing at the firm level.
Of course, firms have compliance departments.
They have, you know,
they issue rules, they issue statements of purpose.
And that's all within firm.
But I wanted to move up now.
Another step in my regulatory thing.
I moved to trade groups.
And these are groups of firms that get together
to form an organization.
So, well, what did I say?
Indra Nooyi was on the U.S. India, what was that?
I don't remember the exact name.
It sounds like a trade group.
A private group that deals with businesses in both.
U.S. India Business Council.
Apparently, business people in both countries got together
and formed an organization where they discuss issues.
And there may be a regulatory function associated with them.
But I wanted to start with
an example of a trade group.
And that is the New York Stock Exchange.
Because it's important in history.
And it was founded in 1792.
In 1792, stockbrokers functioned.
We had a stock market in the United States.
Of course, it was a small one.
The big stock markets then were in Europe.
But there was no organization for the U.S. stock market.
We had our first stock market crash in 1792.
The first American stock market crash.
And within two months, the
stockbrokers set up a trade organization
called the New York Stock Exchange.
And
they met outdoors under a buttonwood tree.
So, they signed a document called the Buttonwood Agreement.
Stockbrokers used to work outdoors.
Even into the 20th century,
the so-called American Stock Exchange
used to be called the Curb Exchange.
That's because they were guys who would stand on
the curb outside of the New York Stock Exchange,
which had a building.
And they would just dicker among themselves and trade.
Then they decided they'd better get a building.
And that became the American
Stock Exchange, which doesn't exist anymore.
It was absorbed by the New York Stock Exchange eventually.
But anyway, the stockbrokers in New
York got together under the buttonwood tree
and signed a historic agreement
setting up the stock exchange.
And it's been described as an idealistic document about
our duties and our duties as a society.
Our duties and our ethics.
But I found actually the text of the Buttonwood Agreement.
And it's really short.
So, I will read it to you.
I'll read you the whole Buttonwood Agreement.
We, the subscribers, brokers for the
purchase and sale of the public stock,
do hereby solemnly promise and
pledge ourselves to each other
that we will not buy or sell our stock,
that we will not buy or sell
from this day for any person whatsoever,
any kind of public stock,
at less than one quarter of one percent commission
on the specie value of gold,
that we will give preference
to each other in our negotiations.
Period.
In testimony, we have set our hands this day,
17th day of May, 1792 in New York.
That's the whole Buttonwood Agreement.
It sounds like a price-fixing agreement.
And excluding other traders.
So, it sounds like a cartel.
I was wondering how I got
the impression that the Buttonwood Agreement
was so idealistic.
Where's the idealism there?
So, I went and I looked
on the New York Stock Exchange website.
And this is their interpretation.
It's on the website right now.
Of the Buttonwood Agreement.
It says there,
at the heart of the Buttonwood Agreement
was the need for fairness, responsibility,
and trust.
Okay.
So, I think actually that might not be as outrageous
a self-serving claim as you might think.
Because what had happened in the 1792 stock market crash,
there was one person who figured very heavily in it.
His name was William Derr.
Am I spelling that right?
It's E, no, it's U-E.
Maybe that was a U, umlaut.
William Derr, who was a stock promoter.
And he got a lot of
people to manage their money for him.
And he got buying stocks on margin.
Encouraged a lot of people to buy stocks on margin.
And,
it created a bubble in the stock market.
Pushing prices up.
Other people thought that Mr.
Derr was not a good character.
But,
he managed to create a bubble in the market.
And it eventually collapsed.
So, it was within two months of that.
Obviously, the stock exchange was
created in response to Mr. Derr.
And so, what they're basically saying is,
we won't do business with this guy.
Because,
we'll close him out.
If we all agree that we won't trade with him,
or people like that,
then they'll be out of the business.
The other thing is, putting a minimum commission on sale.
This is the profit they get from the sale.
It makes it in kind of a gentleman's organization.
Because, they chose a
commission which was sufficiently high,
that they could make substantial money.
And,
they were able to make substantial money trading stock.
I think the philosophy was,
we are ethical members of the community.
We don't want this business to
be turned over to discount brokers.
Who don't care.
And, we will exercise a duty of care.
I wish it said that in the agreement.
I'm reading between the lines here.
I think that probably was part of the motivation.
And so,
we have to keep our incomes up,
so that good people can stay in the business.
That was the philosophy.
And then later, the New
York Stock Exchange adopted many rules
about ethical trading.
And so, they were imposing standards.
It was just not explicit
in the original Buttonwood Agreement.
But,
things changed.
Our attitude toward cartels has changed over the years.
And there's a couple of
important dates I wanted to emphasize.
One of them is 1975.
And it's May Day.
The May Day was May 1st, 1975.
In the United States,
the government under the Securities and Exchange Commission,
was in a state of emergency.
And the New York Stock
Exchange made fixed commissions illegal.
Until 1975,
the New York Stock Exchange was
still following something like the 1792 rule.
Anyone who was a member
of the New York Stock Exchange
had to impose a minimum commission.
And then secondly, they could only trade with each other,
closing everybody else out.
And so, they had to modify that,
because they're closing out the scoundrels.
And so, that prevents a race to the bottom.
But it had another effect.
It was creating monopoly profits.
And eventually,
the Securities and Exchange Commission
said, no more.
We're going to have competitive commissions.
Any effort to fix commissions in
a trade group is now illegal.
And so, the New York
Stock Exchange was closed in 1975.
I think it's interesting, by the way,
that the chairman,
this is a local interest,
the chairman of the SEC,
the Securities and Exchange Commission,
in 1975,
was Ray Garrett,
a Yale College graduate.
And the President of the United States
was Gerald Ford,
a Yale Law School graduate.
So, this had a local beginning.
But I can't claim,
I wasn't lecturing about finance in those days.
Incidentally, that also is the,
1975 is the beginning of the national market system,
which Congress created.
So, there's this idea that you only trade
with other New York Stock Exchange brokers was ended.
Now, brokers have an obligation
to find the best price for their customers
on any exchange.
So, what the government really did
is it broke the monopoly.
And that's why the New York Stock Exchange
has faltered since.
There's so many competitors now.
You've got all these discount brokers.
So, it hasn't done as well as,
if they hadn't made these changes in 1975,
it wouldn't have done as well.
Right now, it's about to be taken over by the
Deutsche Börse, the German Stock Exchange.
So, that's still on, I think, right, that deal?
So, substantially, it was a good deal.
But it was a cartel.
In the United Kingdom, it took a little longer.
But in 1986, when Margaret Thatcher was prime minister,
they had what was called the Big Bang.
That's the British counterpart to May Day.
They deregulated commissions.
And again, it had the same effect.
It broke the monopoly.
So, I could go on a lot about trade groups,
but I think we see some idea that the,
incidentally, the New York Stock Exchange,
even today, has its own market surveillance unit
that looks, it goes through trading records,
and it looks for examples of, say, manipulation.
And they will track down and find you
if they think that something immoral
was done.
So, that even, even though they had a deregulation
of their commissions, they still are doing that.
You know, this idea about regulating,
allowing groups to regulate prices is controversial.
Airlines used to have their fares regulated by the,
what's the U.S. government agency?
The airline fares were regulated at high levels.
And in those days, airplanes would give you great service
because they were competing on service rather than on fares.
So, it used to be that
when you got on an airplane,
there were a lot of empty seats,
because they were scheduling many more flights than needed.
And you got great meals.
But it was expensive.
And so, if they deregulate, fares come way down.
Services, now you're jammed in shoulder to shoulder.
And if you don't like that, you could pay more.
But very few people will pay more.
So, I think on balance, it's
a good thing to deregulate commissions.
And now we have all these websites
now that sell on very low commissions.
It's a product of deregulation.
I mean, a product of regulation, I'm sorry.
Regulation that prevents, I mean, regulation that prevents,
the cartels from forming and closing out competitors
who might charge a lower rate.
So, the third thing I said about local regulation.
This is my third category.
It used to be that
it was a more local phenomenon.
I'm particularly thinking of the United States,
but I think it was true elsewhere as well.
Local banks would be regulated locally
by the people who saw them,
rather than a distant national government.
In the United States, until the 1930s,
financial regulation was almost exclusively local.
The federal government didn't do anything.
So, we had a bunch
of laws called Blue Sky Laws.
That were put in place by
state governments during the Progressive Era.
The Progressive Era was from the 1890s to the 1920s.
That was an era in U.S. history
when a lot of state governments started adding regulations.
They did other things like regulate
food safety and other business laws.
But regarding finance, it was the Blue Sky Laws.
Now, I don't know if anyone
remembers why they're called Blue Sky Laws.
But one interpretation is that there
were a lot of salespeople for investments.
And some of them would
give you an exaggerated sales job.
They would say, there's no limit to how
high the price can go of this stock.
Nothing but the blue sky above.
So, that's my story about how they
got to be called Blue Sky Laws.
But I don't know if there's any
agreement on where that name came from.
But what companies start, what
state governments started to do.
I think the first Blue Sky Law
was in the state of Kansas in 1911.
It was given some impetus by a book
written by William Brandeis called Other People's Money.
It was a book that was published in 1915.
I think it was.
That was a book that
detailed the scandals of fake securities.
Dishonest properties of securities.
And the reason for that was,
because of the fact that the
state government was not a state government.
And the state government was not a state government.
So, they were not a state government.
They were just promoters of securities.
So, it started in Kansas in 1911.
But by the 1930s, practically
every state had Blue Sky Laws.
And they had state regulators that enforced them.
But the problem was that they were state laws.
And it made it difficult for state governments.
There's all these different state governments
that are trying to regulate an industry,
and they're trying to regulate a state government.
And the problem is that the state
government is really national or international in scope.
So, people could evade the Blue Sky Laws.
Now, especially since the telephone
became prominent in the 1920s,
you could set up a
boiler room, so-called, in one state.
A boiler room, I think I said this, is a,
you rent the cheapest space for your telephone bank,
and you pick the boiler room of some,
in the basement of some building,
and you put a bunch of people manning the telephones.
And they call across state lines.
So, this confuses the Blue Sky regulators,
because it involves two different states.
And you call long distance to the other state,
and you give, this used to happen a lot.
It doesn't happen so much anymore.
They would try to sell you on some,
I've got a great stock, it's
going to triple in five days.
If you don't buy it today, it's too late.
And they would get people
into stocks that were utterly worthless.
And it was fraud.
And so, that made it,
the whole progressive movement to regulate securities
was of limited success.
But it left in place a
huge state and local regulatory system
that was considered inadequate to the task,
but which remains today
for the regulation of smaller companies.
The next step is the national regulation.
The national regulation is the regulation
of the United States,
which is the regulation of the United States
under the new deal of President Roosevelt.
So, for national.
Notably, in 1934, I mentioned this before,
the U.S. government set up the,
actually, let me spell it out,
securities and,
exchange commission.
Or SEC.
Which regulates the larger firm.
Practically, any firm that's listed on a stock exchange
would be regulated by them.
They,
one of the,
one of the first directors of
the SEC was William O. Douglas,
a Yale Law professor,
who wrote a book
called Democracy and Finance,
about his experience as SEC director.
And he talked about the,
the conflicts he had with Wall Street at the time.
They really didn't like this regulation.
It was an antagonistic atmosphere.
The Securities and Exchange Commission
was widely regarded in the business community
as practically a socialist organization.
And that's a dirty word in the United States.
Because it seemed like the government was involving itself
in things that they had
no business in involving themselves in.
So, Douglas fought kind of a battle against Wall Street,
as detailed in his book.
But to get everything on an up and up format,
he was following one of the rules that Brandeis,
the thing is, he wanted disclosure.
Louis Brandeis, there's a famous quote in his book,
Other People's Money.
And it is, quote,
sunshine is the best disinfectant.
That's in a parable to hanging out your clothes
on the clothesline and letting the sunlight fall on them
and that disinfects them.
But the same idea applies in finance.
If everybody knows what the firm is doing,
they'll figure it out and there'll be talk.
We just don't want firms to keep secrets.
So, the SEC is built around disclosure.
And so,
I mentioned,
Edgar is their online information system,
but it's on sec.gov.
They put everything up about a company,
that is, of any public company,
up on that website.
And it's free, absolutely free, to the world.
That's disclosure.
And that was the motivating thing.
Another,
SEC chairman,
SEC chairman was Arthur Levitt.
And he wrote a book called Take On the Street
after he left SEC chairmanship.
This was recently,
I mean, like in the last 10 years.
And he told a lot of,
a lot of stories about nasty people
on Wall Street.
He said he had vivid memories
of the reactions he got
from proposed new regulations.
And,
he was particularly upset by the kind of ability
that Wall Street had to fool people by
using complex language that they couldn't understand.
They would write prospectuses that no one could understand
without a law degree.
He wanted plain English.
So, again,
taking a job as SEC chairman
or a commissioner on the SEC
is taking on a high,
high tension job, I think.
But it's all,
it's like the same thing as in sports.
You know how referees in sports
get punched every now and then by the athletes.
But we all see that they're necessary.
So,
one thing that the SEC does
is protects small investors
by managing the distinction,
I mentioned this before,
between public and private securities.
So,
if you want to
go public
and list your security,
the shares of your company
on a stock exchange,
you have to go through a procedure
defined by the SEC
called an IPO.
That stands for Initial Public Offering.
And to do that procedure,
you have to follow a system of rules
dictated by the SEC
that makes it difficult for you to do any shenanigans,
any tricks.
It creates a level playing field.
And the rules are very strict.
And enforced by the SEC.
The SEC allows other companies
to remain private.
But it has rules about what you have to do
to stay private.
Public,
when you become a public company,
you are involved in the public trust.
And you have to,
among other things,
include all of your documents on SEC.gov.
But they do allow private companies.
And a particularly important category
of private company
is the so-called hedge fund.
A hedge fund
is an investment company
for wealthy individuals only.
And there's,
the idea is that
small investors need to be protected.
Because
they don't know,
they can't,
they don't have expensive advisors
and lawyers to tell them what to do.
And so,
lots of controversial things can't be done
in funds that are offered to the public.
A hedge fund
is a fund for these wealthy investors
and the SEC
has minimal regulation of them.
The Dodd-Frank bill,
we thought,
would put more regulation on them.
But they're still surviving
as largely unregulated organizations.
They have different kinds of,
there's different,
the law,
the SEC code of rules is huge
and it's complicated.
I guess you can read about it
on the SEC.gov.
But there's a 3C1S hedge fund.
There's one type of hedge fund.
It can take on no more than 99 investors.
Can't be more than 100.
And they must be accredited investors.
And the SEC defines accredited investors.
That is,
they were proposing to change the definition,
but I think it's still stuck.
To be an accredited investor,
I don't have it here.
I think it's still that you had to
have an income of
at least 200,000 a year
if you're single
or 300,000 if you're married.
Or $1 million in investable assets,
not including your house.
I think that's the definition.
I've got it fairly close.
So, it excludes most investors.
But then there's other kinds of hedge funds.
There's also a 3C7S hedge fund
that's allowed to take on 500 investors.
But these have to have
a net worth of $5 million.
Or if they're an institution,
it can't be a little institution.
So, it would be 5 million.
So, it's more than accredited investor.
It's called super accredited.
5 million for individuals,
25 million for institutions.
That excludes most family foundations, I suspect.
So,
hedge funds,
you don't hear about as much,
because they don't advertise.
And they are not allowed to advertise.
If you click on their website,
you will find a very,
they'll have a website.
It will give you the contact information,
typically,
and say very little more about them.
They don't put anything on their website,
because they worry that they'd run afoul of the SEC,
that the SEC would call it advertising.
And you're not supposed to be for the public.
This creates some conflict.
And I think it's important for people to think,
why is it that the United States
has this kind of two-tier system?
It's not just the United States,
other countries have this as well.
But let's talk about this system.
Why is it that we
have special rules for poor people,
which in effect, in their estimation,
excludes them from some of the biggest profit opportunities.
Hedge funds are allowed to charge,
to impose high management fees.
And the highest management fee
has been called 2 and 20.
2% of the assets under management
goes to the managers every year.
And 20% of any trading profits they make
go to the managers.
Nothing of their trading losses.
If they lose money,
it doesn't come from the managers.
Now, that sounds like a really good deal, right?
Think about it.
If you lose just a billion dollars
in your management fund,
you're getting 2%.
What is 2% of a billion dollars?
That's 20 million.
Did I get that right?
And 20% of the profits.
I mean, you're going to make
a huge amount of money, right?
I suspect some of you will do this,
because it's so tempting.
But of course, you can't do this.
It's not so easy to start a hedge fund,
because the whole idea of a hedge fund
in most people's minds is,
there are genius traders.
And you got to pay them, right?
You can't just hire them cheap.
So, the hedge funds raid all of the geniuses
out of the mutual funds,
which are public investment companies
for these retail investors.
They get the smartest guys
and pay them this huge amount.
And the idea is,
they'll make a lot of money.
Whether they really do make a lot of money
is a difficult question.
It's hard to tell,
because hedge funds haven't been
around, they're changing through time.
I'm sure some of them
do make a lot of money.
Some of them are good investments.
But it's like a wild west.
It's a jungle out there.
And the SEC doesn't think that you,
the small investor,
should get involved in that.
And so, you won't.
That's another example.
So, market surveying,
market surveillance is something
that the SEC does.
And it does it in connection
with the self-regulatory organizations,
like the stock exchanges.
It's again trying to prevent manipulative behavior.
So, I'll give you an example of market,
this is my,
see the markets don't function that well by themselves
without some kind of referee.
The 1792 stock market crash was only one example.
But market surveillance is now
a well-established principle to prevent
manipulators from taking over a market.
I'll give you an example of what happens.
This is a news story from 1995.
In May 1995,
a secretary at IBM Corporation
was asked to copy documents
related to secret plans
to take over the Lotus Corporation.
Okay, Lotus was the spreadsheet,
doesn't exist anymore,
spreadsheet company that
was a pioneer in computer spreadsheets.
So anyway, she just commented to her husband
because she was copying these documents.
She said,
oh, IBM was going to take over Lotus.
Her husband saw that
as valuable information, right?
The stock price of Lotus is likely to go up.
And she said they were going to do it
in three days.
So that's a perfect thing.
So he went,
well, anyway, what did he do?
He merely telephoned all of his friends
and told them,
by the takeover date,
25 people had bought
a half a million dollars
and they were going to take over Lotus.
These people included a pizza chef,
an electrical engineer,
a bank executive,
a dairy wholesaler,
a school teacher,
and four stockbrokers.
Okay.
Well, they caught them
because they saw this unusual activity
in the stock
and they
subpoenaed their phone records
and they figured out who called who
and they called them in and said,
well, I'm not going to tell you
what they've done.
And they were all punished for this.
It's illegal.
You can't trade on inside information.
Again, the SEC is trying to create
a level playing field for everyone.
I'll give you another example.
It was Emulex Corporation,
a former employee of this company,
shorted stock
in his own former company.
And he was,
then decided he would try to help make
the price go down.
So, he sent,
because he knew the company,
he knew how to do this.
He sent a fake press release
to the internet.
And nobody suspected it.
It looked real.
He just sent it out from his own computer.
Actually, it wasn't his own computer.
He thought he was being smart.
He went to the El Camino Community College Library.
You know this story.
Or you know the college.
Well, he went to the library
and he sent the press release
from the library's computer.
And he thought, that's going to be, sure.
And then he,
it worked.
It was picked up by all the news services,
the bad news about Emulex.
And then he immediately sold,
recovered his short position.
And he made a big profit.
And he thought he was smart.
But he wasn't smart enough for the surveillance.
Because they suspected,
well, immediately,
it was Emulex immediately protested.
We didn't send out this press release.
So, the market surveillance team went into action.
And they found out,
it's all in the Stock Exchange record,
who covered a short position
right after the announcement.
They got his name,
as one of the people.
They actually traced down
where the email was sent from.
And they went to El Camino Community College.
And they talked to the librarians.
And they showed them photographs.
And they remembered him.
And so, they nailed this guy.
So, that's an example of what happens in our markets.
And so, that makes things work well.
So, in this category,
I also wanted to mention
what the SEC does with creating private organizations,
or self-regulatory organizations,
that do some of its jobs.
So, we have something called FASB,
which is called the Financial Accounting Standards Board.
It's right here in Connecticut.
The SEC decided that companies
fake their books in too many ways.
There's too much funny business going on.
And we need to manage this better.
But they didn't want to take over completely
this as a government function.
So, the government recognized
an industry group called FASB
as the arbiter of accounting standards.
And FASB is the authority
that defines GAP accounting standards.
And GAP is an acronym
for Generally Accepted Accounting Practices.
I'm sorry, principles.
Generally Accepted Accounting Principles
are defined by a private manager.
It's a private group.
And these principles are used on EDGAR,
which is the website that the SEC
uses to present accounting.
So, they're in Norwalk, Connecticut,
and they have their own website.
And you can see how they define accounting standards.
I'm running out of time here.
I wanted to tell you about
a government agency called SIPC.
I'm just having too much fun
telling you about all these.
SIPC is the Securities Investor Protection Corporation,
created by the United States Congress in 1970.
And it's part of an effort to protect small investors.
The SIPC ensures your brokerage accounts
against losses due to failure of your stockbroker.
It corresponds to the FDIC.
Did I mention this before?
Maybe I mentioned it briefly.
The FDIC is the company that insures your bank account.
SIPC is the company that insures your brokerage account.
And it's a government corporation.
It has limits on the amount that it insures.
It was actually created in 1970 in response.
A lot of things happen in response to a crisis.
There was a brokerage firm called Good Body
that failed in 1970,
just before SIPC was created.
A lot of people had their stocks in Good Body,
and they had accounts there.
And it looked like they were going to lose it.
They held their stocks in street name.
I remember telling you about that.
So, they thought they owned shares,
but really Good Body owned the shares.
Or they thought Good Body owned the shares,
but Good Body went under.
They ran the risk of losing
the shares they thought they owned.
So, SIPC was created in order to prevent that.
And it's a good thing.
Continuing along on the national level,
regulation is getting stronger at the national level.
I'll talk about two examples.
The U.S. and I'm going
to talk about the European Union
as if it were a nation.
It's sort of a nation.
It's an assembly of nations.
But it's kind of halfway between national and international.
I'll start with the U.S.
I mentioned that in the 1930s,
there was a big step up
in regulation with the New Deal,
creating the Securities and Exchange Commission.
The next big regulatory push in the United States
occurred last year in 2010.
And we had the Dodd-Frank Act.
Christopher Dodd was our own senator from Connecticut.
And Barney Frank is the chair
of the House Financial Services Committee.
I'll just give you a
couple of things from the act.
One of them is a,
well, the act is really trying to push regulation more
to the macro prudential from the micro prudential.
All this thing about fraudulent
activities that milk innocent individuals,
that was taken care of by previous legislation.
Well, not all of it. Some of it was.
But the Dodd-Frank creates the
Financial Stability Oversight Council, or FSOC.
The Financial Stability Oversight Council is designed
to worry about too big to fail.
They are the regulator that deals with systemic risk.
That is,
啊
risk that affects the whole system.
They are regulating not just to protect the individual
from bad activities, from being fooled, but also to
protect the whole system.
So that's part of Dodd-Frank.
The other part I was
going to mention is the Consumer
Financial Protection Bureau.
So I'm not sure how to write the acronym.
It hasn't actually taken form yet.
I'll say Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.
This one is a microprudential regulation.
I mentioned her before.
I think Elizabeth Warren proposed it.
She's a Harvard Law professor.
And what it's going to do
is have a government agency that
is focused on
protecting the individual from bad activities.
So it's going to protect small investors or borrowers in
the mortgage market or the like.
Should the last B be P?
Yes, that's right.
I can't write always on the blackboard.
Thank you.
Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.
Elizabeth Warren pointed out, I said this before, that
there's a lot of abusive tactics.
Now, other regulators weren't so focused on protecting, say,
mortgage borrowers or credit card borrowers.
And so, they were more
focused on disclosure and other issues.
So the idea in Dodd-Frank
is, let's create an agency whose
express purpose is protecting the consumer.
The idea is that you have
to have an agency focused on each
problem, and this is a
problem that hasn't been dealt with
well.
I wanted to move to Europe,
because Europe has had a lot of
problems.
I'm going to talk about the problem of the economy.
It's a problem that's been dealt with.
It's had similar legislation, also in 2010.
So, we have the European Supervisory Framework.
And that's also 2010.
And it consists of a number of things.
One.
It's the European Systemic Risk Board, which will be in
Frankfurt.
Well, which is.
I think they're just getting started.
European Systemic Risk Board is the European counterpart to
FSOC.
All these things are brand new,
and so we don't know too much
about how they're going to function yet.
But it's supposed to worry about
too big to fail and about
systems.
About systems.
How the whole European economy could function.
How the whole European economy could collapse, if something
goes wrong in the future.
Then there's the European Banking Authority.
These are big steps for Europe, because regulation was more
done by the individual countries.
And the European Banking Authority is in London.
And it will impose Europe-wide banking regulations.
And then we have ESMA.
The European Securities Market Authority.
And that's in Paris.
And then there is the European Insurance and Occupational
Pension Authority.
And that's in Frankfurt.
They spread things out across Europe.
They don't want to centralize things.
I don't know why Frankfurt got
two of them, but somehow that
worked.
And finally, I want to do international.
If I could just have
five more minutes of your time.
International regulation is a problem, because people can
leave the country that they're in.
And it's called offshore.
If you don't like the regulations in the United
States, there's always the Bahamas, or there's the Cayman
Islands.
And you can set up your financial organization with
the regulator that you please.
That's why it's important for international cooperation in
regulation, so that all the financial activity doesn't
migrate to the cheapest place,
or the cheapest in terms of
regulatory cost.
But I just wanted to give
you a few more institutions that are
important.
One is the Bank for International Settlements.
That's in Basel.
This is the oldest of my regulators.
Actually, when we get on the international front, they don't
really have authority anymore.
They can't impose on anyone, but they can suggest things.
So, the BIS is a bank that
has as members heads of, I think
it's 57 central banks, and
they meet regularly in Basel to
discuss monetary policy.
So, what comes out of these meetings is success.
And it's a great way to
give suggestions about how to run a
central bank.
And it has real impact, even
though it doesn't have the force of
law.
Then I wanted to mention the
Basel Committee, also in the same
city.
You notice these are in Switzerland.
That's because by long standing,
it's been a neutral country, and
it has such a long tradition of neutrality.
So, it seems to be the place
to set up a lot of international
relations.
This was created in 1974, and it issues suggested bank
regulation.
Basel I was in 1988.
That was their first set of recommendations.
Basel II was in 2004.
And obviously, Basel II wasn't successful,
because we had a huge banking
crisis.
And then, we had Basel III.
I'll come back to these in 20,
well, it's been going on for years.
It was finally approved, Basel III, in 2010.
Then I wanted to talk about the G6.
Going back to the 1970s,
the finance ministers in six major
countries met together.
The countries were France, Germany,
Italy, Japan, United States, UK.
In 1976, they added Canada,
and it became the G7 country.
So, that's Canada, France, Germany, Italy, US, UK.
Who am I missing?
Japan.
So, these seem to be the
most financially prominent countries at the time.
And their finance ministers got together
and thought about what the country should
do, and it coordinated financial regulation somewhat.
This expanded notably.
I'm just about done now.
In 2008.
The world is changing.
And there was resentment that these
countries represent overwhelmingly Europe and the US,
or the North America.
We created the G20 countries in 2008.
And I don't have the whole list, but it
consists, it notably adds China and India, and adds
other developing countries.
It now represents most of the world.
Again, it's the finance ministers.
Well, typically what happens now is the finance
ministers will meet, and after that, the heads
of state will meet.
And it's involved in financial regulation.
The current president of the
G20 is Nicolas Sarkozy from France.
And he intends to make it a stronger organization.
He has proposed that they have a permanent secretariat.
The G20 has created something called the FSB.
The Financial Stability Board.
And guess where it is?
It's in Basel.
You can't, everything goes to, any of these
things that are really, if it's European Union,
they'll scatter it around the EU.
But if it's really international,
it seems to go to Switzerland.
Basel is a sleepy little town, if you visit
it, but somehow, it's the center for the world
finance.
So, the Financial Stability Board
is making recommendations for regulatory procedures
and other regulations.
And it's a very important part of the EU.
It's a very important part of the EU.
Because the Financial Stability Board is
making regulatory procedures for the whole world.
And they report to the G20, and then
the G20, they've already agreed to take FSB seriously.
So, I think maybe I'm, yeah, I think,
so what I'm seeing here is developing is, the
financial regulation is becoming more and more large-scale.
And it's something that covers the whole world.
And it's very important.
Because we've just seen it.
We've just seen a worldwide financial crisis.
And it has to be dealt with by worldwide.
I think this is an
inspiring moment for financial regulation.
The G20 seems to be an effective
body that is promoting good financial regulation.
At this point, this is a good time
in history, where there's a lot of cooperation.
And if it continues, and we see this
develop further, it will make for more successful
world economy.